Contact

jay@neue.world

www.linkedin.com/in/jayant-rao (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

UI UX

User Experience (UX)
User Interface Design

Languages

English

Hindi

Marathi

Kannada

Certifications

Bachelor in Multimedia Design

Honors-Awards

Awwwards Honors - Safe Society Awwwards Honors - Foglia D'Oro CEOs in UAE

Top B2B Design Design Firms - UAE

Jayant Rao

Design Agency Founder | Webflow | Creative Strategy | Consultant | UI UX | Combining Design with Organic Growth

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Summary

As the founder of Neue World, a UI/UX agency, I help clients turn their visions into engaging, user-friendly digital products. I have a Bachelor's in Multimedia Design from Raffles Millennium and a passion for storytelling, problem-solving, and design.

I follow the double diamond process with four phases: discovery, define, develop, and deliver. I build solid foundations before starting any project, regardless of the deadlines. I have successfully delivered high-quality designs for clients across various industries, such as EMAAR NEXT, THE LIST, and Featherlite. I have also received multiple Awwwards honors for my web design projects, such as Safe Society and Foglia D'Oro.

I am not just a service provider but a partner and a collaborator. I have bootstrapped my business from zero to seven figures purely organically. I am involved in every step of the project with my team, and I focus on each solution's why, how, and what. I believe in creating experiences that hook the users and the customers and make them fall in love with good design.

Experience

Neue World - UI/UX Agency Founder April 2021 - Present (3 years 5 months)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

We're storytellers, problem-solvers, over-thinkers, and even designers, if you'd please! We are Neue World, a design agency with focus on the need rather than the want. We believe in building an experience that hooks your users and your customers, to a point they fall in love, because good design can truly make you feel things - and that's what we're chasing!

We're not perfect and we understand neither is the end customer, but that's exactly where we come in. That sweet spot of empathy and design, that's what we do for you!

Emaar Dubai Lead Product Designer March 2020 - April 2021 (1 year 2 months) Dubai

Redefining loyalty programs.

THE LIST

4 years 9 months

User Experience Designer August 2016 - April 2021 (4 years 9 months)

Web Designer

August 2016 - January 2020 (3 years 6 months)

Dubai, United Arab Emirates

Product Design + Tech and Business.

Currently acting as a Product Manager for Web and UX Lead for iOS App; a bridge between Design, Stakeholders and Business Goals.

Featherlite

Creative Head

June 2015 - July 2016 (1 year 2 months)

Bengaluru Area, India

Job Profile

- Handling the digital front of the company.
- Product Design (store.featherlitefurniture.com)
- Generating video content for product promotions on Social Media and eCommerce.
- Formulating and maintaining a design language
- Designing new collaterals for product promotion and advertising
- Web Design for store.featherlitefurniture.com
- Coming up with ideas for eCommerce expansion

What I also did:

- Maintaining presence in all social media and planning campaigns to generate organic reach

- Manage an agency which takes care of our social media presence
- Approval of content, creatives and articles to be posted on social media and blog
- Keeping an eye on Analytics of our website
- Keep an eye on weekly progress results after SEO and SEM done by agency
- Handling Magento by updating stocks, product listing and keeping an eye on new orders
- Generating sales on eCommerce using social media
- Coming up with promotional campaign to generate more sales

Ogilvy & Mather Advertising

Research Associate

April 2015 - August 2015 (5 months)

Research data, behavior, opinions, beliefs, challenges, hopes, ideas and preconceived notions of Millennials.

This included behavior study of youth in public and one-on-one interview with filtered millennials ranging from wide variety of lifestyles.

TedX Bangalore

Lead Designer

June 2014 - August 2014 (3 months)

Lead Designer incharge of the whole branding for the event handing digital and print design.

Ogilvy & Mather

Intern

January 2014 - August 2014 (8 months)

Working with the mainline team which includes the VP and ECD of the company. Giving in my ideas and visual outputs, handling and leading projects whenever required. Taking lead of projects which suit my abilities and skills. Basically, learning about corporate companies by learning from the professionals and the experienced.

Education

Raffles Millennium

Bachelor in Multimedia Design, Multimedia · (2012 - 2015)